in brain organoid news the guy who
allowed brain organoids to Pilot a robot
drone spider has made another huge
advancement first off I've talked to
Allison he seems like an awesome person
but sir you are a mad scientist in kind
of a good way what they've done is
guided brain organoids into developing
into something that is much more similar
to a fetal human brain the researchers
have even said that the
electrophysiology the brain activity is
comparable to a human fetal cortex
historically as brain organoids have
been made they've ended up a little bit
funky and inconsistent they may have all
of the structures expected in a fetal
human brain or they may be missing some
sometimes they have eyes sometimes they
have eyes in the wrong place and they
almost always expire of hypoxia after
just 100 days because they don't have a
functional vascular system but what
they've managed to do is keep them alive
for longer than 10 months and they've
gently guided the structures into
becoming the correct structures in the
brain and have done it consistently and
while yes is kind of spooky it has a lot
more applications than just making
potentially one-day conscious robots we
can use them to model human diseases in
fact they've even been used to
demonstrate that chronic wasting disease
is not likely to transfer to humans and
other types of organoids like lung
organoids have been used to model human
diseases imagine a world where you could
have your own organoids made and
medications could be tested to see if
they would have a good outcome that
includes the potential for using these
guys to take samples of tumors and
actually test what medications will work
taking a lot of the guest work out I
would say these guys have a lot of
potential to be used in a very
beneficial way and a lot of potential
for abuse too